december 23rd 2018 egg log
the server has descended into chaos
a series of events has led to the
formation of two factions
both are under the illusion that this
war has meaning
a contingency plan to prevent a prank
war was futile
no matter how many eggs were thrown
they just kept pranking
it just kept
escalating
now the two sides have established
headquarters on the island to settle
their differences
a ceasefire has been called while they
prepare their fortification for what is
to come
there's little i can do for this server
anymore
i will have to go into hiding until this
is all over
i have no choice but to blend in to
normal hermit society
who knows when this feud will truly
begin
until this thing is over
no one is safe
i wish
i was joking
but i'm not
[Music]
this is poultry man
end transmission
[Music]
well everybody i am officially back to
work i took a pretty big break it's been
a long time since i've uploaded a video
and i'm very excited to be back you can
see that the winter skin is off i'm back
in my normal clothes and i'm standing on
a brand new building that you just saw a
brief time lapse of this is the official
g-team headquarters it's obviously not
finished we did a few hours time lapse
me stress and iskall have put this
together and yes it looks roughly like
the little bad drawing that i made and
here's what it looked like for reference
it's not too far off the mark and we've
got a lot of work to do to make this
look even better so you can see it's a
big giant tower it kind of looks like a
futuristic folder or something but it is
really cool it is the same palette as my
base over there so
yeah it's actually looking pretty good
and we had a lot of the resources ready
to go
i think today i want to work on this a
little bit more this is what i made
before the break here and this is a
little bunker we've got a few things
like a little concrete maker down here
other than that we've been collecting
lots of resources and we're pretty much
ready to start properly now the feud
will not begin straight away that flag
needs to stay up for a few more days
because
i don't know about you but like that's
not looking like a finished base
and that's not looking like a finished
base i think when we all took a break
over the christmas holidays it was a
proper christmas break so i'm hoping
that all of you had a fantastic new year
and a break but now it is time to get
back into the work so i think we will
come back to this a little later on we
need to head over to the base because i
have been doing a few odd jobs
off-camera since i was away and to be
honest with you not a lot of people have
been doing much on the server that is
new actually the mall has a
weird hive on it but other than that not
a lot has changed you can see up the top
here i've actually been adding some
greenery to my little avery i've
actually finished putting some leaves on
these trees in fact it probably could do
with a little bit more i ran out very
very quickly but it looks quite nice
especially when you're down here but for
some reason you might remember last time
that there was one chicken in here well
now there's
way more and i'm not really sure where
they have come from because
these chickens
i'm pretty sure they don't just breed on
their own right oh oh goodness
oh they're
all getting stuck in there i didn't
really think this through did i i've
kind of blocked the path well it makes
it a little bit harder to get out yeah
well like i know where these guys were
going
down in my base it's exactly the same as
where we left it just a little bit
messier and even more chickens
unbelievable
has mumbo
has mumbo topped up that machine again
i thought i got rid of all of these i
don't know whether these are just
leftovers from before or if these are
new so we're gonna clear all of them out
and then if more appear we we know that
there's a new machine i just heard i
just heard a machine but i don't know
whether you know that is really clever
because these make noises all the time
so i don't know whether mumbo's built a
new machine in here or if it's just this
thing going off
oh my goodness is he
uh i'm gonna be forever finding chickens
everywhere poultry man has gone into
hiding like properly look
the door has been closed
it doesn't work anymore
the coop has been properly shut up i
cannot get in at all i think it's
probably for the best that we leave it
for now
since i'm a little bit out of date let's
go and see what our good buddy mumbo
jumbolio is up to
his base is as laggy as ever
oh i can really feel it i can feel it
when i get in here i wonder if okay so
he must have got rid of the chicken
machine that was coming out of here well
he hasn't actually got rid of it he
didn't get rid of the chickens i think
he just disabled the redstone i think we
won't we won't make it too obvious by
putting it back together now look at
this it makes it too easy we'll just
leave that there for now let's see what
he's up to
so he's got his creeper farm here and
he's got all of the machines now what is
this thing
huh
villagers something to do with villagers
what on earth is this machine and why is
there oh
oh what the heck is is it like a it's
like a delivery system for villagers i'm
so confused on so many levels
poor girl this poor guy
i'm so sorry there's nothing i can do
for you
there's absolutely nothing i could do
for you is he collecting village there's
loads of them this is inhumane well you
know what you do you mumbo
you do you
whatever it is you're up to i'm sure it
has a purpose maybe he's making some
sort of iron golem farm or something but
whoosh weird
let's head back to the g team hq because
we need to get on with some of the
building there to get some work done i
think an issue is we need something at
the back of this but i'm not sure
exactly what
i think we've definitely got to have
like our meeting room somewhere up here
i'm thinking what if we have like a
platform that kind of semi-circles
around here
and then we also have another one up
there so it's like an oh it's all of
this area is completely open but we have
like a two-tier system yes this looks
incredibly like the avengers tower and
that was kind of the plan from the
get-go so if you guys are getting that
kind of vibe we succeeded this is all
definitely the calm before the storm so
obviously there's a lot of fun
shenanigans on their way
but because everyone was like taking
such a proper break over the christmas
holidays
not a lot of stuff has actually been
done at all so
we've all got like a bit of a rush now
in early january to catch up and get
this made and get our ideas and i've
actually been working on a separate
video for like
uh not pranks as such well yeah totally
pranks pranks and traps and stuff so i'm
hoping that i can share some of like my
ideas with you in like a separate video
that the hermits won't know about really
and then we can sort of decide which of
those would would be most suitable
for this prank war going on
i'm not entirely sure what to do with
every single part of this build it is a
little bit freeform and i do wonder if
this like
floor here will then show through the
glass and look super weird so maybe we
should take a look from an outside
perspective
you know what that doesn't look too bad
probably because like it'll be cool to
be able to see inside like i think this
is where the meeting room should be and
like the viewing platform obviously
nothing important should be up here
because if there is anything important
it could get this is like the most
exposed area of the entire operation so
we definitely and like all of these
materials they blow up really easily so
we don't want anything too important up
here but we still got to make use of
this space this is our this is our way
of seeing what they're doing we got such
a perfect view of everything we've got
the height advantage see if i look out
the window um i see what you're doing
over there weird star fort thing i
wonder what they're going to build on
top of that because at the moment it
looks like it's just the foundation
layer
so it could end up being rather
formidable
i figure that this thing here where the
beacon is i think the beacon can
probably move or be removed when we're
done with building but i think this is
probably a really good place to have
like a water elevator because you can
like go up and you can see everything i
think that would be a really neat place
for one so i'm thinking that the second
layer can go here as i've just finished
this one now i'm thinking that the main
table goes here but i think i'm gonna
leave that for clio or stress or someone
else because they also said that they
wanted to do that so if i leave a sign
for them
so i've left a little sign here for
zombie glio saying you said meeting room
here is the perfect place so i'm
wondering if i can get like a really
cool staircase maybe going up the side
i'm not sure if that's possible but i
think that would look really really nice
one thing that's really bad about the
tower is we can't really hide anything
up here all of our valuable stuff will
likely have to go underground because
this tower is mainly for show and
incredibly vulnerable so this is where
we could have like our meeting room the
the watchtower stuff but there's no way
we can hide stuff here it's just
too out in the open it's so easy i mean
you can see inside the meeting room from
just outside the building and that's not
very good that's not a bad start it does
actually bring this together a bit more
and that actually looks pretty good from
the outside as well despite being able
to see directly inside
that's not really a big deal because
we're not hiding anything in this tower
i don't think one thing it does need
though is some branding we have
absolutely zero branding where's the
giant g on this thing you know and i
think we should make it out of quartz
block which means another trip to the
nether and it has actually been fixed
since the last time i was here it was an
absolute state before it was like half
and half never
oh my goodness look at the progress that
has been made on this i guess i took for
granted just how big of a project this
really is
so i've been like slugging away a little
bit of this i've got nearly 20 000
blocks mind but false false is making me
look
shameful she's got
000 blocks mind
that is absolutely insane i guess i
should probably do a little bit more
since we need a bit of quartz or i guess
i'll just mine it until i get the amount
that i need
oh no oh no
oh no
i think that's a good time to leave oh
my goodness
oh what have i done i think that's
probably oh
man
oh i was just idly mining and then i set
them all off
i made them all angry i managed to do a
couple thousand actually like 4 000
blocks and that equated to nothing i
just made a big mess as you can see i
don't think i ever really explained the
whole plan for the nether hub or maybe i
did and i can't remember but essentially
we're creating a giant map of the entire
server and it's going to be block for
block perfect within the whole nether
thing so if you go to the somewhere like
if you went over to my base on the mini
map in the nether you will get and go
through the portal you will then get to
my base and cubs asking who hit the pig
man i said no idea an idiot probably
oops
i think we can assume that mumbo did not
build something in my base because i've
cleared out those chickens and nothing
else is spawning in having said that
i
i i
i thought
i thought i could hear something
at that
i was like having said that i hear
chickens but i don't see any chickens
what's he done now is it the same
machine as he just edited it what has he
done i'm confused here
ah
i think i found the source of the noise
i think
little mustached mumbo over there
desperately tried
to put these chickens where i wouldn't
hear them
by putting them lower but he failed as i
could hear them
down they go
oh wait no is that just gonna get
oh no what have i done oh no
i think i've said it on a clock no no no
no no stop stop stop
[Laughter]
well we can't we can't let him get away
with this can we i think we need to i
think we need to pay mumbo back with
something else that i didn't build in
his base
but i think it shouldn't even be chicken
related anymore i think we can do
something else
but i'm just not sure what yet leave me
some ideas in the comments and i'll have
a little browse and see what i can come
up with
looks like these guys are still
collecting oh i think it got stuck mumbo
mumbo your system mumbo your system's
broken here i'll help you out go on
onwards on you go go on
don't worry i've got you fella go on in
you go
oh he's not going in is he there you go
i think i should tell mumbo that his
system
doesn't quite work yet
wait is that mumbo there
well well well
what have we got
[Laughter]
you guys saw that right
that was some quick reactions by me
whoo
did he even see me
uh oh yeah he
saw me i wasn't even up to anything i
don't know why i was so scared i was
just checking on him
he he's just afk even though his
system's broken look his system is
broken and he's afk and just waiting for
it to fill up mum okay look i'm gonna
have to get his attention
mumbo mambo
mambo
oh i actually hit oh i actually hit him
mumbo
he's taken off all his stuff
[Music]
you're right villagers maybe we are the
fork of friendship i can't take this box
of goodies i'm just trying to help him
out mumbo
please your machine isn't working
wake up
how do i make
a huge amount of noise
well if you can't beat them join them
i'll be here when you get back mumbo
i'll be here
ah
ah he's back
hello
hello yes you have a problem and it's
not me we need to get out of here
i'm trying to punch oh
i'm sorry mama
i mean
[Music]
oh he's just trying to get out
look okay he's finally here look your
little fellas are stuck i'm trying to
i'm trying to i'm trying to help you
look up here this little fella he's
stuck
ah finally don't worry gerald we got his
attention he's gonna save you for
whatever is
weird villager contraption is about him
i may have had to punch him in the face
to get his attention but don't worry
he's gonna put you nice and safe with
all of your friends down there with all
of your brothers and sisters i guess i
guess i can send him on his way right
mumbo says thank you
and you're in
off he goes
good luck gerald i look forward to
finding out what this this whole thing
is about well that is a good deed well
done
[Laughter]
that was quite that was actually quite a
good dive there i'm impressed mumbo
oh there there's another one oh we can
see what happens to him
so what's going on
he goes he goes up in his little car
he's drowning
and then he falls down
to the next layer
uh
well i'll leave you to fix it mumbo and
uh whatever your whatever it is you're
doing i look forward to finding out what
it is moving back to the g team base i
think we need to start building
something underground and we haven't
even gone anywhere underground yet so i
think it's about time we created one
what we really want to find here
is
a ravine because i had a really cool
idea for an underground part of the base
so i don't really want to have to dig my
own ravine
however i would really like to find one
and i feel like aimlessly digging around
is definitely not the way to do it
i hear some water that's uh that's a
pretty good sign water could mean
ravine or just a normal cave
even a normal cave would do it to this
point
ah just a normal cave no wait
it's oh my goodness it's actually a
ravine
this is perfect this is just this is
like straight under the base
i think
it must be look that i just got the
haste back ace2
oh this is brilliant this is exactly
where i want to make the underground
portion but i think
we actually need to make this ravine a
bit wider manually which kind of sucks
but
but this could work really well so i
think that's what we might work on next
time while the other guys finish up
working on the interior of the tower and
maybe we can get parts of that done as
well but overall i think the whole base
will be coming together very quickly
over the next few days we've just got to
keep slugging away at it to make up for
all the lost time ah what a stroke of
luck i was sure that this was just a
normal cave
well anyway i think that is enough for
today's episode thank you very much
everyone for watching i hope you enjoyed
it and it's good to be back and i hope
you are excited to have hermitcraft back
as well so thank you very much for
watching everyone and good bye
you